# Rithvik Rajani Kanth Sasi



rithvik.career@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/rithvikrs



& https://www.rithvik.ml



# https://github.com/RithvikRS



# **Summary**

I am currently studying at Vellore Institute of Technology in Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science with specialization in Bioinformatics. I have received a Presidential Award from President Obama for academic excellence. I have studied in the United States of America for 5 years. I have studied in the various curriculum include IGCSE, K-12, and CBSE.

## **Experience**



## Member

**Developer Circles from Facebook** 

Dec 2019 - Present (1 year 8 months +) Member of Facebook Developer Circle Vellore, and Chennai area



#### **Core Committee**

Jan 2020 - Mar 2021 (1 year 3 months)

## **Education**



## Vellore Institute of Technology

Bachelor of Technology - BTech, Computer Science 2018 - 2022



## Saraswathi Vidyanikethan Public School - India

2016 - 2018



## 🔙 Dawn International School

2014 - 2016

## **Licenses & Certifications**



AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner - Amazon Web Services (AWS)

Issued Jul 2021 - Expires Jul 2024

- Introduction to Programming Using Python Microsoft

  Introduction to Programming Using HTML and CSS Microsoft

  SQL Database Fundamentals Microsoft

  Machine Learning Coursera

  MCLB7UFXLEUA

  Introduction to MongoDB Coursera

  4WDCCCGCMQTJ

  Fundamentals of Parallelism on Intel Architecture Coursera

  SDYNUKYSH8AP

  Bioinformatic Methods I Coursera

  FV7TXFYMH2XU
- C3Z7MD8BD48B

Java Programming: Solving Problems with Software (with Honors) - Coursera

- Java Programming: Arrays, Lists, and Structured Data Coursera
  TUX2MCLL3BVQ
- Machine Learning with Python Coursera
  VE4Q3M7B6U85

Al For Everyone - Coursera

HATN56K2RRMD

- Introduction to SQL DataCamp 599994db9656099bdccb257dae23adfd57a4a049
- Machine Learning with Python Coursera e586a166-a357-4a44-8e87-c279812b5976
- Introduction to Python DataCamp
  3c687df3c98cadae15390627020d52a703e4a0bb
- Intermediate Python DataCamp 68c4e4ea40dd654c70de207066514f65f4024fa7

- Python Data Science Toolbox (Part 1) DataCamp ca3bd93b21e18c62a2ad4356945985a357e8ef2c
- Python Data Science Toolbox (Part 2) DataCamp f00b772f6f7d726a6ee0f3ff76995a0c9ef95499
- Bioinformatic Methods II Coursera
  EZM4X7QD29Q3
- Neural Networks and Deep Learning Coursera
  H3L38XV2SMQE
- Introduction to TensorFlow for Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, and Deep Learning Coursera

  YMRP7AHMBMKH
- Transfer Learning for NLP with TensorFlow Hub Coursera
  4B8CR4MPUBVB
- Build a Face Recognition Application using Python GUVI Geek Networks, IITM Research Park
  DI72GT621X9J1h11W5
- Guinness World Record Participation GUVI Geek Networks, IITM Research Park 78001HT3z92636lghB
- AWS Academy Graduate AWS Academy Cloud Foundations Amazon Web Services (AWS)
- Programming for Everybody (Getting Started with Python) Coursera K3RUU78ZNDRL
- Python Data Structures Coursera
  85QZBMRBU3XF
- Algorithmic Toolbox Coursera 8S579H4DNJYE

## **Skills**

Python (Programming Language) • C++ • HTML5 • Object-Oriented Programming (OOP) • Data Science • Artificial Intelligence (AI) • Java • Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) • Web Development • PHP • JavaScript • Bootstrap • Machine Learning • Deep Learning • C • Neural Network • Data Structures • Algorithm • Bioinformatics • MongoDB • AWS • Digital Forensics (FTK Imagery, Autopsy, ProDiscover Basic, Wireshark) • Cloud Computing • AWS

#### **Honors & Awards**



Given for Academic Excellence from President's Education Award Program.

Honor Roll - Superintendent Of Schools California, and House Of Delegates, Virginia Four Honor Roll, two from Superintendent Of Schools in California and two from Member, House Of Delegates in Virginia.

# **Projects**

- Road Safety using number plate detection
- Spam Detection with Google Gmail API
- Malicious URL detection
- Portfolio Website
- Real-time Mask Detection using Machine Learning(with IOT additions)
- Lane and Object Detection
- Library Management and Delivery System
- Hospital Management System
- Movie Recommendation System
- Game Recommendation System
- Movie Web App (with global chat)